

### **Computer Science Graduate**



Highly motivated and enthusiastic Computer Science Graduate with an interest in full time work and internship opportunities related to software development. I am confident that the software development experience I have gained at work and school, coupled with my soft skills such as being a great team player and communicator, would help me to have a positive contribution towards overall growth of your company.

### Education

### BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE | SHERIDAN COLLEGE

2016 - 2021 | Oakville, ON

- Languages learned: C/C++, Python, Java, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, Swift
- Related courses: Data Structures & Algorithms (1), Wireless Security (2), Software Engineering (2), Artificial Intelligence (2), Scripting & Web Languages (2), OS Analysis & Design (1), Business Intelligence & Data Mining (2)

## **Major Technical Projects**

## **WORD SEARCH GAME | MOBILE APP**

NOV 2020 - JAN 2021 | Oakville, ON

- · A word search puzzle game for Android where the user must find all hidden words in a grid of letters to win
- · Developed with Java in Android Studio
- · Tools used in development include Android SDK, JSON, and Gradle
- · GitHub Link: https://github.com/AlexanderVhd/Word-Search-Game

# **JOBPILL** | MOBILE APP

FEB 2020 - DEC 2020 | Oakville, ON

- · Mobile job search and recruiting platform that allows users to search (provides ability to filter) and post jobs
- · Developed with Java in Android Studio
- Tools used in development include *Android SDK*, *Gradle*, *Firebase* cloud hosted data storage, and the Google Cloud Platform's machine learning *Vision API*

# ALEXANDERVHD.IO | WEBSITE

JUL 2020 - NOV 2020 | Oakville, ON

- · A responsive portfolio website
- · Technologies and tools used in development include Bootstrap framework along with HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- · Website Link: https://alexandervhd.github.io/

# TWEET COUNTER | CONSOLE

OCT 2019 - NOV 2019 | Oakville, ON

- · An application that implements a custom map reduce algorithm on a large twitter data set
- · Counts the frequency of the most used words in a person's tweets
- · Developed with Python
- · GitHub Link: https://github.com/AlexanderVhd/DM-Map-Reduce-Program

### **Skills**

SOFT SKILLS

SOFT SIMILES	I ECHNICAL SKILLS	
Team Oriented	Java	Flask
Communication	Python	SQL Scripting
Time Management	C/C++	Android/IOS Development
Detail Oriented	HTML/CSS	Bootstrap Framework
Reliable & Accountable	JavaScript/TypeScript	Pandas
Problem Solver	React	Data Structures

TECHNICAL SKILLS

## **Work Experience**

### **OAKVILLE PUBLIC LIBRARY**

Innovation Accelerator Team Member (Part of Sheridan Program)

FEB 2021 - APR 2021 | Oakville, ON

- · Worked with a team of 2 others to design a strategy for how OPL can effectively make improvements to its services for library patrons amidst the pandemic
- · Connected with OPL to determine their needs and existing strategies in place
- Developed UI wireframes (using Figma) for a prototype room booking feature to be integrated into the current OPL mobile app
- · Delivered a pitch to OPL executives for the room booking feature, receiving positive feedback and a 90% grade

### THE HOME DEPOT

Sales Associate

MAR 2019 - MAY 2020 | Oakville, ON

- · Informed customers about various services as well as products and their details in store
- · Sold heavy-duty products to customers (BBQs, Sheds, Lawn Maintenance Equipment)
- · Handled online customer orders and curb side pickup

### **SELF EMPLOYED**

**Python Tutor** 

JUN 2018 - AUG 2018 | Toronto, ON

- · Clarified concepts of programming principles as well as Python logic and syntax
- · Assisted in troubleshooting problems with code

### **INE LANDSCAPING**

Lawn Maintenance Specialist

JUN 2015 - JAN 2021 | Oakville, ON

- · Provided quotes on lawn care for customers
- · Worked in a team for lawn care through clean ups, lawn cutting, lawn fertilizing and lawn aerations